（カラスの鳴き声）
（邦枝祖父）ここが魔二津じゃ。→
This is Mapputatsu.
Mapputatsu: Literally "Demon Twin Peaks"
古くから伝わる修業の場として
名を知られてきた。
It's known as a place used
for training since long ago.
（男鹿）滝か…。
（鬼塚）なるほどの。
A waterfall, huh?
I see.
（黒木）何がです？
See what?
バカか　おめ～。
滝で修業とくれば…って　あ～！
What, are you dense? When you talk
training with a waterfall, you...
（三鏡）はっは～！
素早さも強さのうちだぞ。
Being fast is part of being strong, you know!
クッ…てめえ！
妙に似合ってんじゃねぇか！！
Bastard...
For some reason you look
really suited for that.
（黒木）あの　老師。
修業というのは…？
Um, Master?
About the training?
うむ。まずは
基本からという事で…。
（一同）おう！
Right. I figured we'd start with the basics.
Right!
石を拾ってきなさい。
（一同）エッ！？
Please go gather a stone.
I Must Become Stronger
ヘックシュン！ったく…→
クソー！あのじじい
だましやがって…。
Damn that old bastard... He tricked me!
（邦枝）
勝手に先走ったんでしょ～が。
Except it was you who jumped to conclusions.
（出崎）だけど　石拾いねぇ…。
But man... Gathering stones?
一体どういう修業じゃ…。
What kind of training is this?
まあ　石なら何でも
い～んだろ…。ん？
He wants a stone, so anything'll do, right?
（２人）やんのか　コラッ！？
Oh, it's on!
なんでケンカしてんのよ！
Why are you fighting?
（鬼塚）わしは…→
This one...
こいつじゃあ～！
...is mine!
（２人）なっ…なにぃ！？
W-What?!
フフフッ
これくらい朝飯前よ！
I can handle this much before breakfast...
震えてんじゃね～か。
You're shaking like crazy.
ちょっと！
こんな事で　いちいち…ん？
Hey! Don't start fighting
over each and every thing!
（ベル坊）ウー…！
（光太）アー…！
（邦枝）あんた達も何してんの！？
And what are you two doing?!
アイッ…。
ビエ～～ッ！！
なんで　俺だけ～！？
Why just me?!
ふむ。石と
言ったつもりじゃったが…→
Well, I said stone, not
boulder, but no matter.
まあ　よいか。
《こ　これは…》
T-This is...
《確かに修業になるのぉ…》
...really part of our training?
では次に　おのおの持ってきた石を素手で割ってもらう。
Now then, next...
I want you to split the stone you
brought with your bare hands.
（一同）はぁ！？
できるまで飯抜きじゃ。
And no meals until you manage it!
No, not a chance...
ふっ…。おっ　おい…？
Hey...
ハァーッ！！
セヤッ！
痛っ…。
って　無理に決まってんだろ
じじい！
You old fart! There's no way that's possible!
だよな。アホなのか…？
Seriously...
Is he an idiot?
しかし　老師。
やはり　無理ですよ　これは。
But Master... This is impossible, yes?
瓦を割るのとは訳が違います。
This is far more difficult
than splitting roof tiles.
ふん…そう思うか？
Ah... Is that what you think?
葵。
はい。
Aoi!
Yes.
（三鏡）《おいおい　まさか…》（鬼塚）
《あの娘が素手であれを…？》
Whoa there... Don't tell me...
That girl is going to split
it with her bare hands?
（出崎）《うそでしょ～》
You've gotta be kiddin' me!
（黒木）《持つだけで
精一杯ではないですか》
She's winded just from carrying it...
よ～く見ておきなさい。
必要なのは力ではない。
Now watch closely!
What's necessary isn't power!
撫子…。
Nadesico...
（一同）うおおおっ！マジ！？
Seriously?!
ふ～。
（祖父）撫子。心月流の
基礎の基礎じゃ。
Nadesico.
The very basis of the Shingetsu
School's techniques.
衝撃を分散させず
一点に集中させる当身。→
Attack focusing all your energy on a
single point instead of spreading out.
達人になれば　下の岩だけ
砕く事もできる。
Once you master it, you can even
break only the stone on the bottom.
大事なのは力の伝え方→
The important thing is how you use your power.
呼吸　姿勢　そして集中力じゃ。
Breath, posture,
and concentration.
どうじゃ　少しはやる気に…。→
How about that? Starting to get motivated?
全く聞いとらんのぉ…。
They're not listening at all, are they?
すげぇ　マジで真っ二つだ！
Wow, it's seriously split right in two!
Mapputatsu can also mean "split in two"
これを　女子の手でのぅ…。
That girl did this with her bare hands?
うん…。
真っ二つ…。
Mapputatsu... Split in two...
あっ　そうか！だからここは
魔二津という名前に！！
That's it!
So that's why this place
is called "Mapputatsu"!
違うと思うわよ…。
No, I don't think so.
（ボス）緑色の髪のガキ？
知らねぇなぁ。→
A kid with green hair?
Never heard of 'em.
ここはガキの来る所じゃ
ねぇんだぜ？
This ain't a place for brats.
スカルヘッドの名前くらい
聞いた事あんだろ？
I'm sure you heard of the Skullheads, right?
この辺りじゃ最強のチームだ。
なあ　兄ちゃんよぉ。
We're the strongest team about here.
Ain't that right, Bro?
（古市）
また分かりやすい
不良の方で。
Great. More easy-to-read punks.
ああっ！？
（古市）あ　いえ　何でも…。
Huh?!
Oh, nothing.
勝手にウチらのシマに
入ってきやがってよぉ！
You just barged into our territory, buddy!
覚悟は
できてんだろうな！ああ！？
You'd better be prepared
for the consequences!
（寧々）古市。→
Furuichi!
ああ　やっぱここか。
寧々さん。
Oh, so this is where you are.
Nene-san...
あんたね　ここは
いいって言ったでしょ。
Look, I told you not to
bother with this place.
ど～せ
いやしないんだから。
He ain't gonna be here.
いや…ゲームセンターは全部と思って。
But I thought we should
cover all the arcades...
寧々！？
レッドテイルの大森寧々だ…。
Nene?
That's Omori Nene, of the Red Tails!
なんで　こんな奴と一緒にいるんだ！？
Why the hell is she with this guy?
ああ？誰だい
いま呼び捨てにした奴。
（不良たち）ヒィッ！
Huh? Who was that who just
said my name disrespectfully?!
（ボス）レッドテイルの
四代目様か。→
The 4th leader of the Red Tails, huh?
だが　いくら　てめ～でも→
But even you are getting cocky if you think
you can come in here all by yourself...
ひとりで乗り込んでくるのは
無用心じゃね～か？
ひとりに見えるかい？
Do I look alone to you?
てめえら　やる気か！？
離れろ　コラ！！
You bastards! You wanna do this?
Let him go, you!
（ラミア）はぁ…何これ？
いつも　こんな感じなの？
What the heck? Is it always like this?
まあ　何故か大体
こうなる事が多い。
Well, things like this happen
in the summer a lot...
《ってゆ～か　これ
人数的にヤバいんじゃね？》
But wait... Aren't we
kind of outnumbered here?
くくっ　うれしいねぇ。
Wow, I'm so happy... Two
pretty ladies by my side...
両手に花だな　こりゃ。→
俺らと本気で
戦争しようってか？
Do you really wanna go to war with me, huh?
（神崎）おい　いつまで
ダラダラやってんだ。
Hey! How long are you gonna take?
（姫川）向こうのゲーセンにも
いなかったぜ？
He wasn't in the arcade
across the street either.
がっ　がはっ！！
（神崎）ん？ああ…
スカルヘッドか。
Huh? Oh. The Skullheads.
（姫川）なんだ　てめ～ら
もめてんのか？
What? You have a problem?
（古市）いや　ちょっと…。
Well, kind a...
か　神崎と姫川じゃね～か…。
I-Isn't that Kanzaki and Himekawa?!
なんで　東邦神姫が…。
バカ！目ぇ合わすな！！
Why is the TKKH here?!
Crap! Don't make eye contact!
（ボス）す…。
（不良たち）すんませんっした～！
W-We're so sorry!
（神崎）おう。（姫川）次行くぞ　おめ～ら。
Yeah.
Let's move on to the next one, people.
（バンッ！）
っしゃあ～！どうだ　オラ～！！
How about that, huh?!
孝ちゃん　すごい！おお…。
Ko-chan, you're amazing!
あと１歩
というところですかね。
Just one more step, I suppose.
ム…。
男鹿！あなたも意地張ってないで小さい石にしなさいよ。
Oga. You need to swallow your
pride and try a small stone first.
ものには順序ってものがあるんだから。→
First things first, you know.
そんな岩　たぶん
私でも無理だと思うし→
Frankly, I think even I
couldn't split that stone.
本当に　あなただけ
ごはん抜きになっちゃうわよ。
At this rate you're the only
one that'll be skipping supper.
男が意地張んなくて
ど～するよ。
What's a man without his pride?
いっぺん決めた事だ。
やり切ってみせら。
もう…。
I've made my choice, and
I'm gonna follow through.
Honestly...
《とは言ったものの
ど～すっかなぁ…》
Is what I said... But what should I do?
《マジで割れる気がしねぇ》
This thing ain't splitting, not even close.
《ベル坊の力を使えば
簡単なんだろ～が→
It'd be a cinch if I used
Baby Beel's power, though.
それじゃ意味ね～し…》
But that's not going to help.
ム～　アダッ！
アーイ～…！！フッ。
ムム…オッ！
何が　して～んだ？おめ～らは。
Seriously, what are you
two trying to accomplish?
（三鏡）おやおや～？お前まだ→
Well look at this...
You're still trying to split that stone?
そんな岩　割ろうとしてんの？
身の程をしらね～なぁ。
You seriously don't know when to quit.
何なら俺がコツを
教えてやろ～か？
How about I teach you the trick to it, huh?
先にマスターした　オ・レ・が！
The one who mastered it first, me!
ん？
そうだな…。
That's it...
ちょっと手伝ってもらうぜ。
え…？
Would you help me out a sec?
スーパーめり込みパ～ンチ！！
Super Burying Punch!
割れた～！
I split it!
（祖父）うん…
こういうんじゃないのね…。
Um, that doesn't count.
Understood.
わかった。調べさせてた奴から
連絡あったぞ。→
I've got word from my people
I sent to investigate.
緑色の髪の奴が
ゲーセンで暴れてるらしい。
There's someone with green hair
making a scene in an arcade.
Making a scene?
暴れてるって…。
まさか…。
You don't mean...
（焔王）エーン　エーン…！
い　急ぎましょう！！
W-We've got to hurry!
Found ourselves a green haired kid...
緑色の髪の毛　発見。
（真田兄）
おら　ジャンプしてみろよ　ああ！？
Come on. I said jump!
Stop being confused for other people!
紛らわしい事
してんじゃね～よ！
何なんだ　てめ～ら！？
What's wrong with you people?!
Look! Green hair!
いた！緑の髪。
（ＭＫ５たち）あはははは…！
（ＭＫ５たち）ダメだこりゃ～！
MK5
Defeated Instantly
（下川）グッナ～イ！
出てくんな！！
Good night!
Don't jump in!
（下川）グッナーイ！
Good night!
MK5+1
Defeated Instantly
（石の割れる音）
ふぅ。
これで　全員コンプリートじゃの。
Now we've all completed it, right?
Okay, everyone help out!
さ　じゃあ　みんな手伝って。
もうすぐ　カレーできるわよ。
The curry is almost ready!
うむ。さあ　メシだメシだ！
（三鏡）メシだ！じゃね～よ。
Yes! Time for food!
"Time for food!" my butt!
ギャグアニメじゃなきゃ俺　死んでるとこだぞ！？
If this wasn't a gag anime I'd be dead!
That's quite honest of you.
律儀な格好ですね。
自業自得じゃ。
It's your own damn fault.
ムー…。う～ん…。
男鹿。
あん？
Oga!
おお　うまそうじゃ。
Oh... Let Baby Beel eat.
ああ　ベル坊だけ
食わしてやってくれ。
But...
でも…。
い～から。
It's fine. I think I'll
get the hang of it soon.
もうちょっとで
コツがつかめそうなんだよ。
ハァ…。
（ベル坊の　おなかの音）
Beel-chan, let's go and eat first, okay?
ベルちゃん　先に食べよっか。
ダ！
♪～　ナンダッタッター
ナンダッタッター
ベ…ベルちゃん…？
Beel-chan?
♪～　ダッダッダブダブダー！
男鹿！ちょっと…。あん？
Oga, hey!
What is Beel-chan doing?
（邦枝）
ベルちゃん　何をしてるの？
What?
何って…食事前のお祈りに
決まってんじゃね～か。
He's doing a blessing before his meal.
♪～　ニャンダッタッター
ナンダッタッター…
Don't go teaching babies stupid crap!
くっだらね～事
赤ん坊に仕込んでんじゃね～よ！
I didn't teach it to him, baldy.
別に仕込んでね～よ　ハゲ。
知らね～のか？
Don't you know?
悪魔の王族ってやつは
儀式を重んじるからな。
Rituals are very important
to Demon royalty...
Hilda does it sometimes, too.
ヒルダも　たまにやってるぞ。
Sorry, but I haven't a clue
what you're talking about.
（三鏡）
すまん　何を言ってるのか
さっぱり分からね～んだが…。
ダッ！
トーッ！フッ　セヤッ！！
クッ！ハァハァハァ…。
ふむ。今日は　ここまでじゃな。
That's enough for today.
Go to the temple near
here and spend the night.
近くの寺まで行って
そこで１泊じゃ。
You heard the man! Hey, Oga!
だとよ。おい　男鹿！
ハァハァハァ…。
Oga! That's enough for today, got it?
男鹿！とりあえず今日はここまでにしなさい。
ん…。
男鹿！
Oga!
う…。ってえな　何すんだ　コラ！
That hurt!
What's the big deal?
Look, you're a mess!
ほら　もうボロボロじゃない。
明日にしなさい。
Start again tomorrow!
嫌だね！嫌だ　嫌だ…。
な！い～から！
ここまでにしなさい！
I don't wanna!
Enough!
That's enough for now!
No!
嫌だ！…あ。
ほら　行くわよ。
Come on, let's go.
邦枝ちゃんなら　あの岩を割れちゃうんじゃね～か。
I bet Kunieda-chan could split that stone.
（鬼塚）おお。
（出崎）スゴイわね～。
Wow...
Wait... We can really stay here?
つか　こんなとこ
泊まって　いいのか？
The head priest here is
an old friend of mine.
ここの住職とは　昔からの→
知り合いでな　遠慮はいらん。
Make yourselves at home.
（住職）いらっしゃい　邦枝さん。
お待ちしていましたよ。
Welcome, Kunieda-san.
We've been expecting you.
あ…これは　どうも。
うむ。世話になるの　住職。
Thank you very much.
We're in your care, Head Priest.
Isafuyu!
諫冬。
（４人）お…。
（住職）お客様を　ご案内しなさい。
Please lead our guests.
Isafuyu-chan, Isafuyu-chan!
諫冬ちゃん　諫冬ちゃん！
ど～ゆ～字　書くの？
What kanji is your name
spelled with? It's so cute!
カワイイね～。中学生かな？
Are you in middle school?
You are such a flake.
（鬼塚）お前はホント軽いの～。
U-Uh...
（諫冬）あ　あの…。
やめなさいよ　怯えてるじゃない。
Stop it, you're scaring her!
（鐘の音）
You can stay here in the main hall.
（諫冬）こちらの本堂に　お泊り
いただきます。
あり？邦枝ちゃんは一緒じゃないの？
Wait, you're not staying
with us, Kunieda-chan?
残念でした　私は
おじいちゃんとこです。
Sorry, but I'm staying with Grandpa!
Ooh, this is cool, Baby Beel.
お～すげぇぞ　ベル坊。ア～。
Check it out.
見てみろ　大魔王だ。
The Great Demon Lord!
N-No...
ち　ちが…。
ん　どうした？
ニョ。
What's wrong?
う…。
プ…嫌われたな　男鹿！
She hates your guts, Oga.
（諫冬）葵ちゃん。
いさちゃん　久しぶり。
Aoi-chan!
Isa-chan, it's been so long.
Sorry about today.
ごめんね　今日は。
（諫冬）ううん。
It's okay...
Seriously, this really helps out.
いや　助かったわい。後で礼に行くでの。
I have to thank you properly later.
Um, Father said you could use the bath.
あの　お風呂
沸かしたからって　お父さんが。
Really? Thanks a lot!
ホント！嬉しい。汗で　もう
ベトベトなの。おじいちゃんは？
I'm all sweaty...
What about you, Grandpa?
I'll go last.
ワシは最後でいい　あの
悪ガキたちを先に入らせなさい。
Let those delinquents use it first.
'Kay!
は～い。ねえ
いさちゃんも一緒に入ろ。
Hey, Isa-chan! Let's go together!
う　うん。
Okay!
ん　サービスカット。
Service cut!
Destroyer!
（鬼塚）デストレイラー！
Destroyer
Demon Rock Headlong Dash
But seriously, this bath is amazing.
つ～か　マジすげぇな
ここの風呂。
Yes. It's like a bath in a
hot springs vacation hotel.
ええ。温泉旅館のようですね。
（邦枝）
≪ああ…。いさちゃん家のお風呂
やっぱ広くて気持ちいい≫
Isa-chan, your bath is so
wide open... It feels great!
Kuroki... You just thought
of peeking, didn't you?
黒木。お前　今
覗けるかもと思っただろ。
い　いえ
私は　そんな。
No, I wouldn't...
しょうがねえな～。
Guess I gotta do it, huh?
なんじゃ覗くのか？
What? Peek?
No, no, no! That's very wrong!
（黒木）いやいやいや！
ダメですよ　絶対。
Kuroki!
（三鏡）黒木！男なら
やらずに後悔するより→
Men act first and deal with
the consequences later!
やって後悔しろ　だ。
（２人）三鏡…。
Mikagami...
We can hear you.
聞こえてるから。
Um...
あの　赤ん坊を背負った
男の人の事だけど。
About the man who is raising the baby...
え？お　男鹿が　どうかした？
I-Is there something up with Oga?
Yeah...
うん。その…→
He's...
悪魔だよね　あの赤ん坊。
...a demon, isn't he?
That baby...
Isa-chan, you can tell?
いさちゃん　分かるの？
うん。何回か　悪魔に憑かれた人
見た事あるから。
Yeah. I've seen people haunted
with Demons a number of times.
そっか。いさちゃん
霊媒体質だったよね。
I see...
You've always been sensitive
to the paranormal, Isa-chan.
You can sense Demons and stuff like that.
悪魔とかも分かるんだ。
でも　あんなにスゴイのは
初めて見る。
But that's the first time I've
seen one that incredible.
How can I put it...
何ていうか…。→
There's something fundamentally different
than the ones I've seen before.
今まで見て来たのとは
格が違うっていうか。
《魔王だしね》
'Cause he's a Demon Lord, I guess.
But wait... You can do exorcisms
and stuff too, right Isa-chan?
あれ？でも　いさちゃん
お祓いとかも出来るのよね。
え？う　うん。まあ…。
Yeah, I guess...
Wait... Do you know a
way to beat Demons, too?
ね　もしかして　悪魔をやっつける→
方法とかも知ってるの？
え？
If you do, then teach it to me!
だったら教えて！
葵…ちゃん？
Aoi-chan?
In the end, you couldn't
even put a crack in it.
結局　ひび１つ入れる事も出来んかったの。
（男鹿のおなかの鳴る音）
ふん。意地を張らずに
出来る所から始めたらどうじゃ。
Why don't you swallow your pride and
start with something you can handle?
うるせぇよ。地道に力を身につけていかんと→
Shut it.
Unless you develop your own strength gradually,
悪魔の力など
いつまで経っても→
you'll never be able to
use the Demon's power...
使いこなせんぞ。
何で知ってんだ。
How did you know?
見れば分かるわい　そんな
ふざけた赤ん坊がおるか。
I can tell just from looking.
Have you ever seen a baby as crazy at that?
Seriously?
マジか。
自分の力のなさを
認めるんじゃな。
You've accepted that you lack strength.
But being in a hurry isn't
going to get you anywhere.
焦って　どうなるもんでも
ないわい。
…ん。
（クラクション）
So?
（寧々）どう？
We've searched everywhere... I think we
need to change strategies or we're screwed.
こんだけ捜して　いね～となると。
ちょっと捜し方を→
かえね～とダメだな。
捜し方っすか？
Change how we search?
何か　ね～のか？ゲーム好き以外の手がかり。
Don't you have any clues
other than he likes games?
So?
ど～なのよ？
う～ん。でも　あとは　もう…。
ヒルダ姉様のメールにあった→
But the only other thing...
In a mail to Miss Hilda, he said
"Online games are the greatest!"...
ネトゲサイコーっていう言葉しか。
え？
そ～いや　あのガキ…。
Now that you mention it, that brat...
Yeah... He said something about heading
to Akiba and buying an online game...
ああ　何かアキバに行って
ネトゲが　ど～こ～。
That's it!
え？何が　どれ？
What? I don't get it.
（いびき）
（出崎）孝ちゃん　やめて
やめないで…。
ぐ…。ぐ！
う…。く。
（祖父）
((地道に力を身につけていかんと
悪魔の力など→
Unless you develop your own strength gradually,
you'll never be able to
use the Demon's power...
いつまで経っても使いこなせんぞ。自分の力のなさを→
You've accepted that you lack strength.
認めるんじゃな。焦って
どうなるもんでもないわい))
But being in a hurry isn't
going to get you anywhere.
分かってんだよ　んな事は。
I know.
I know, damn it!
う！でも…。
But...
う…地道に
行ってる場合じゃ　ね～んだ。
...time isn't a luxury I have!
今は…焦るしか
ね～だろうが。
Hurrying is the only choice I got!
It's morning! Up and at 'em!
朝よ。ちゃっちゃと起きて！
Oga?
男鹿？…まさか。
Don't tell me...
Damn it, that fool!
《ったく　あのバカ…。
あんな大きな岩→
That giant stone isn't something you
can split in one day of training!
一朝一夕で割れるもんでも
ないでしょうが…》
…ウソ。
No way...
ハア　ハア…。
Oga?
男鹿！？
Look here, you... What'll we
do if you get yourself hurt?
（邦枝）あんたねえ
こんな無茶して→
体　壊したら
ど～すんのよ。
This ain't gonna be enough
to beat those guys.
あいつらに
勝つためには　まだまだ→
こんなもんじゃ足りね～んだよ。
ピーヒヒヒ。
（光太）まいりました。
Don't worry, you'll get stronger.
（邦枝）大丈夫。
強くなるよ　あんたは。→
As long as you have the will... For sure!
その気持ちが　ある限り…絶対！
（おなかの鳴る音）
Now then, let's have breakfast!
さ　ご飯にしましょう。
（鳥のさえずり）
Damn that old man... Splittin' stones,
and now some "special course"?
くそ…あのじじい
岩を割ったと思ったら→
何が特別メニューだ　こんなとこ
登らせやがって。
Makin' me climb all these stairs...
ん？
ニョ。
てめえ…。何で　ここに。
It's you...
Why are you here?
Hey, is that any way to talk?
（早乙女）おいおい　つれねぇな～→
And I'm skippin' school for this.
学校休んで来たってのに。
Welcome, you piece of crap.
よう　クソったれ。
修業…後半戦だ。フフフ。
Time for the second half of your training.
Ooh, you did it, Baby Beel!
Our training's going well!
How about you, Furuichi?
We're going fine, too! Lord
En is hooked on online games.
Next time is the long
awaited gaming showdown!
My special moves are gonna
explode off the screen!
On the next Beelzebub:
Play Games at Most One Hour a Day!
What? An hour isn't long enough?
We don't have time for games!
Everyone, watch anime!
And when you do, make
sure it's Beelzebub, yo!